The Reese Family Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- The Mesier Family, 1700 - 1891; 2; Boxes: 15 - 23 Folders: 1 - 21, 1 -34, 1 - 41, 1 - 43, 1 - 12, 1 - 44, 1 - 28, 1 - 12, 1 - 2
  - Miscellany, 1761 - 1882; 2.5; Boxes: 21 - 23 Folders: 1 - 28, 1 - 12, 1 - 2
    - Abstracts and titles of the Mesier Estates of Wappingers Falls, circa 1800s (Folder 1, Box 23)
    - Tilley Brunson (admission to the Holy Orders of Deacons and Priests by the Bishop of the Episcopal Church in Connecticut), 1785 September 21, 1788 February 24 (Folder 2, Box 23)
    - Receipts book, 1759 - 1761 (Folder 3, Box 23)
- The Willis Family, 1802 - 1880; 3; Boxes: 23 - 26 Folders: 4 - 26, 1 - 10, 1 - 16, 1 - 14
  Series contains correspondence, materials pretaining to Francis Willis, and Miscellany.
  - Correspondence, 1831 - 1880; 3.1; Boxes: 23 Folders: 4 - 20
    - William Henry Willis, 1831 February 18 (Folder 4, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1838 (Folder 5, Box 23)
    - Willis Brothers, 1839 (Folder 6, Box 23)
    - Willis Brothers, 1841 January 13 (Folder 7, Box 23)
    - Willis Brothers, 1843 January 3 (Folder 8, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis and Alfred Willis, 1847 January 12 - 1848 May 17 (Folder 9, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1848 December 6 (Folder 10, Box 23)
    - Alfred Willis, 1849 April 16 - 18 (Folder 11, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1854 February 7 - 1850 December 10 (Folder 12, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1854 July 8 (Folder 13, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1855 March 11 - May 1 (Folder 14, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1864 May 5 - June 3 (Folder 15, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1860 November 12, 1862 December 15 (Folder 16, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1863 June 4 - 1865 May 26 (Folder 17, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis (letter from United States Secretary of State Hamilton Fish), 1873 October 25 (Folder 18, Box 23)
    - William Henry Willis, 1880 September 16 (Folder 19, Box 23)
    - Correspondence, undated (Folder 20, Box 23)
  - Francis Willis, 1861 - 1870; 3.2; Boxes: 23 - 24 Folders: 21 - 26, 1 - 10
    - Correspondence, 1863 August - 1864 July (Folder 21, Box 23)
    - “Resolutions made at the time of Confirmation”, undated (Folder 22, Box 23)
    - Archery laws, undated (Folder 23, Box 23)
    - Note from Doctor Beales excusing Francis Willis from military duty, undated (Folder 24, Box 23)
    - Bankbook, 1870 May (Folder 25, Box 23)
    - Notebook, 1865 (Folder 26, Box 23)
    - Diary, 1869 (Folder 1, Box 24)
    - Diary, 1870 (Folder 2, Box 24)
    - Short stories by Francis Willis, circa 1864 (Folder 3, Box 24)
    - Notebook (Columbia College Law School), 1861 (Folder 4, Box 24)
    - Notebook (Columbia College Law School), 1861 (Folder 5, Box 24)
    - “The Earnest Communicant”, 1868 (Folder 6, Box 24)
    - Portable chess set, undated (Folder 7, Box 24)
    - “The Teacher’s Manual”, undated (Folder 8, Box 24)
    - Baccalaureate degree (Columbia College) [Latin language], circa 1865 June (Folder 9, Box 24)
    - Translation notebooks [2 items], 1861 - 1862 (Folder 10, Box 24)
  - Miscellany, 1802 - 1876; 3.3; Boxes: 25 - 26 Folders: 1 - 16, 1 - 14
    - Marriage certificate (John R. Willis and Martha Willis), 1802 November 10 (Folder 1, Box 25)
    - Newspaper clipping (poem by W. H. W.), undated (Folder 2, Box 25)
    - Journal of a tour to Europe by John R. Willis, 1839 (Folder 3, Box 25)
    - Selections of prose and poetry (Lydia Waring), 1828 (Folder 4, Box 25)
    - Passports (John R. Willis), 1839 - 1843 (Folder 5, Box 25)
    - Letter from William Henry Willis to Lydia Willis [French language], 1830 December (Folder 6, Box 25)
    - Mr. Webster’s second speech on the Sub-Treasury Bill delivered March 12, 1838 (William Henry Willis), 1838 April 16 (Folder 7, Box 25)
    - Abstract of title of William Henry Willis and Edward Willis to leases of two lots on Second Avenue, 1805 (Folder 8, Box 25)
    - Sale of original sketches in water and oil (descriptions and prices of items sent to William Henry Willis), undated (Folder 9, Box 25)
    - Receipt of William Henry Willis for carpentry work, 1857 May 6 (Folder 10, Box 25)
    - St. Nicholas’ Society constitution and by-laws, 1850 (Folder 11, Box 25)
    - Passport (William Henry Willis), 1847 (Folder 12, Box 25)
    - The Willis family tree from 1598 to 1862, circa 1862 (Folder 13, Box 25)
    - Sketches of the works for the “Tunnel Under the Thames” from Rotherhithe to Wapping published by Harvey and Darton, 1831 (Folder 14, Box 25)
    - Small purse, undated (Folder 15, Box 25)
    - Kitchen inventory, undated (Folder 16, Box 25)
    - Certificate of Arrival (William Henry Willis), 1842 May 10 (Folder 1, Box 26)
    - A journal of a tour to the Falls of Niagara, 1824 July 10 (Folder 2, Box 26)
    - Small notebook (William Henry Willis), circa 1848 (Folder 3, Box 26)
    - Receipts for shares of stocks (Washington Fire Insurance Company), 1871 December 29 (Folder 4, Box 26)
    - Agreements between William Henry Willis and Edward Willis, 1876 October 6 - 1877 January 17 (Folder 5, Box 26)
    - Receipts (William Henry Willis), 1848 December 11 - 1871 February 28 (Folder 6, Box 26)
    - Insurance policy for the Board of Education of School District Number 5, Fishkill, Dutchess County against loss or damage by fire or lightning, 1869 April 26 (Folder 7, Box 26)
    - Accordion organizer (William Henry Willis) [see file 9], circa 1861 (Folder 8, Box 26)
    - Contents of accordion organizer [see file 8], 1861 (Folder 9, Box 26)
    - Receipts (William Henry Willis), 1853 - 1865 (Folder 10, Box 26)
    - Lease from the National Bank of New York to William Henry Willis, 1870 February 11 (Folder 11, Box 26)
    - Road Warrants (William Henry Willis) [2 items], 1862 April 1, 1863 March 31 (Folder 12, Box 26)
    - Newspaper clippings (William Henry Willis), circa 1860s (Folder 13, Box 26)
    - Memorandum notebook (William Henry Willis), 1869 (Folder 14, Box 26)
- The Stevens Family, 1721 - 1856; 4; Box: 27 Folders: 1 - 9
  Series contains family documents
  - Family Documents, 1721 - 1856; 4.1; Box: 27 Folders: 1 - 9
    - Copy of the will of John Stevens, Boston, Massachusetts, 1721 March 31 (Folder 1, Box 27)
    - Copy of the will of Erasmus Stevens, 1744 March 14 (Folder 2, Box 27)
    - Three typed copies of letters written to Byam Kerby Stevens from his sister Mary, 1816, 1817 (Folder 3, Box 27)
    - 1796 Indenture - Deed of a gift of land in Albany from Comfort Sands to his daughter Frances Sand (Folder 4, Box 27)
    - Deed of land in Georgia from Comfort Sands to Frances Sand, 1796 April 22 (Folder 5, Box 27)
    - Deed of land in Brooklyn from Joshua Sands to Samuel Stevens, 1817 November 24 (Folder 6, Box 27)
    - Sketch and photo of Albert G. Gallatin, undated (Folder 7, Box 27)
    - Letter to Byam Stevens from Albert Gallatin Stevens (brother) regarding his will, 1856 December 31 (Folder 8, Box 27)
    - Resolution of condolences on the death of William Stevens by his classmates in the class of ‘66, undated (Folder 9, Box 27)
  - 4.2: Ebenezer Stevens, 1763 - 1839; 4.2; Boxes: 27 Folders: 10 - 62, 1 - 61, 1 - 8
    Series contains official documents, business and personal correspondence, military correspondence and papers, and miscellany
    - Official Documents, 1791 - 1805; 4.2.1; Box: 27 Folders: 10 - 13
      - Notice of the appointment of Ebenezer Stevens in charge of the Field Artillery for New York, signed by Governor John Jay, 1797 (Folder 10, Box 27)
      - Appointment of Ebenezer Stevens as Brigadier General of the Militia of New York signed by Governor John Jay, 1799 (Folder 11, Box 27)
      - Appointment of Ebenezer Stevens to post of Brigadier General of the Brigade Artillery signed by Governor George Clinton, 1804 (Folder 12, Box 27)
      - Appointment of Ebenezer Stevens to the post of Major General of the Artillery signed by Morgan Lewis, 1805 April 16 (Folder 13, Box 27)
    - Business correspondence, 1787 - 1817; 4.2.2; Box: 27 Folders: 14 - 47
      - Memorandum of May 1787, Saratoga from General [Philip] Schuyler instructing the purchase and payment of supplies, 1787 May 22 (Folder 14, Box 27)
      - General [Philip] Schuyler from Albany to Messrs. Stevens and Connolly regarding a wheel drill from London, 1787 July 17 (Folder 15, Box 27)
      - General [Philip] Schuyler memorandum to Stevens and Connolly regarding the payment of 16 pounds to Smith and Wycott in behalf of George Beale, undated (Folder 16, Box 27)
      - Letter to Colonel Ebenezer Stevens from Fisher Ames in Philadelphia, 1791 January 13 (Folder 17, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Oliver Wolcott in Philadelphia, 1793 November 13 (Folder 18, Box 27)
      - Letter to Colonel Ebenezer Stevens from Rich Varick in New York City, 1793 December 4 (Folder 19, Box 27)
      - Letter to Brigadier General Van Cortlandt, Coronel Stevens and Captain Randall from George Clinton regarding his appointment as President of the Society of Cincinnati, 1794 July (Folder 20, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Samuel Ruggles regarding his son, 1794 October 13 (Folder 21, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from J. Marshall regarding Norfolk officials, 1796 April 15 (Folder 22, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from James Henry, War Department, Washington regarding the delivery of shells, fuses, and apparatus, undated (Folder 23, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Thomas Pickering, Department of State regarding ship bound for Tunis, 1800 January 30 (Folder 24, Box 27)
      - Washington letter to Ebenezer Stevens from J. Marshall regarding the merchant vessel with merchant stores, 1800 December 27 (Folder 25, Box 27)
      - Washington letter to Ebenezer Stevens from James Madison regarding shipping military supplies to Tunis, 1801 May 4 (Folder 26, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from George Clinton regarding $20,000 for fortifications, 1801 July 6 (Folder 27, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from James Madison, Department of State regarding a pass for the ship “Peace and Plenty” and a letter to go to the Consul at Tunis, Requesting Stevens supply necessary Visas and papers, 1801 July 17 (Folder 28, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from James Madison regarding ships returning from Tunis and fee to be paid, 1802 February 18 (Folder 29, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from James Madison, 1802 June 6 (Folder 30, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Moreau. Letter is in French, 1805 February (Folder 31, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from John Jay, Bedford, New York, 1805 February 8 (Folder 32, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Horatio Gates ordering wine bottled, 1805 August (Folder 33, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Thomas Jefferson sending a money order to cover cost of wine order, 1806 May 5 (Folder 34, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from James Madison Department of State regarding vessels burned by Admiral Allenmand and promise of restitution, 1807 January 28 (Folder 35, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Governor Morris, 1807 April 12 (Folder 36, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Albert Gallatin, Treasury Department, 1808 March 22 (Folder 37, Box 27)
      - Washington letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Thomas Pickering regarding the embargo against Britain. His letter mentions effect on British Empire, with references to France and Napoleon. This letter is an interesting commentary on foreign policy, the president and his advisors., 1808 January 26 (Folder 38, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Thomas Pickering asking Stevens to keep his Spitzenberg wine in the ground for him until he arrives to pick it up from Colonel Van Renselaer [Rensselaer], 1810 March 9 (Folder 39, Box 27)
      - Division Orders of New York State Artillery. Orders of Major General Stevens by WB Crosby, aide de camp, 1811 June 28 (Folder 40, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Issac [Isaac] Brooks of Boston, 1812 December 19 (Folder 41, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Benjamin Weld, 1813 March 4 (Folder 42, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Robert Ralston of Philadelphia, 1816 November 22 (Folder 43, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Thomas Pickering in Washington with a request for the costs of living in New York, 1816 December 6 (Folder 44, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Thomas Pickering regarding a trip to New York by steamer, 1817 March 10 (Folder 45, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Rufus King regarding pensions for veteran officers of the Revolutionary War, 1817 December 12 (Folder 46, Box 27)
      - Additional typed copies of the letters contained in this subseries, various (Folder 47, Box 27)
    - Military correspondence and papers, 1812 - 1813; 4.2.3; Boxes: 27 - 28 Folders: 48 - 62, 1 - 8
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from William Pawling, Jr., Adj. General [adjutant], 1812 April 17 (Folder 48, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from William Pawling, Jr., enclosing a copy of the orders of the 21st issued by an act of Congress regarding the war. The orders are not included with the letter, 1812 April 25 (Folder 49, Box 27)
      - Inspection forms for battalions to be used by the Commander in Chief, 1812 May 4 (Folder 50, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Governor Daniel Tompkins requesting Stevens organize 2 battalions from the artillery and offering advice on which majors should head the battalions, 1812 May 12 (Folder 51, Box 27)
      - Brigadier General Morton request for a report for the non-compliance of a brigade order of July 4th. Enclosed is the report from Aide de camp Major Mullin (?), 1812 July 8 (Folder 52, Box 27)
      - Letter from Daniel Tompkins to Ebenezer Stevens regarding the artillery at Sag Harbor, 1812 July 23 (Folder 53, Box 27)
      - Memo from the Brigade Quartermaster of the Artillery with a list of commanders of the regiments, 1812 July 23 (Folder 54, Box 27)
      - Letter from Daniel Tompkins regarding the placement for new volunteer troops on Staten Island to protect New York City and the harbor, 1812 August 31 (Folder 55, Box 27)
      - List of arsenal used in campaign, 1812 July 21 (Folder 56, Box 27)
      - Titled “Places of Rendezvous of the Brigades of Regiments of the Militia of the Service Division commanded by Major General Ebenezer Stevens.” Penciled chart., circa 1812 (Folder 57, Box 27)
      - Inspection return of the 10th Brigade of the Infantry in New York commanded by General Steddiford, January 1813. Report signed by the Aide de camp of acting Brigade Major. The report details regiments, officers and arms., 1813 January (Folder 58, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens accepting Stevens’ offer to serve as his Aide de camp, 1813 June 1 (Folder 59, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from the General of the Cavalry, 1813 June 3 (Folder 60, Box 27)
      - Orders of Pierre Van Cortlandt outlining the places of rendezvous in the southern district of New York, 1813 June 18 (Folder 61, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Abraham Rose regarding the troop movements, 1813 June 18 (Folder 62, Box 27)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from General Steddiford explaining the inspection report (see 3.11), 1813 June 19 (Folder 1, Box 28)
      - Bridgehampton. Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from General Rose discussing arrangements for rendezvous of troops in the event of invasion, 1813 July (Folder 2, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Jackson Odell enclosing copy of the orders of the 15th brigade (no orders are in the letter), 1813 July 1 (Folder 3, Box 28)
      - Letter from General Isard stating that he cannot authorize US Government troops, 1813 July 15 (Folder 4, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Governor Tompkins authorizing General Rose call out 100 men, 1813 July 12 (Folder 5, Box 28)
      - Letter to Governor Tompkins from General Rose in Sag Harbor, 1813 July 19 (Folder 6, Box 28)
      - Letter from the Commissary of Military Stores. Request for powder and ball, 1813 July 26 (Folder 7, Box 28)
      - Scarsdale, Westchester. Lieutenant Colonel Durian discusses the readiness of men and munitions, 1813 September 12 (Folder 8, Box 28)
      - Report of the 3rd Brigade of Infantry, 1813 October 7 (Folder 9, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Governor Daniel Tompkins, 1813 August (Folder 10, Box 28)
      - Orders from the War of 1812, 1812 - 1813; 4.2.3.1; Box: 28 Folders: 11 - 41
        - War of 1812 Orders - bundle cover labeled “also correspondence with General Bloomfield” [following reflects the original order of the bundle], 1812 April (Folder 11, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders (Folder 12, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 July 29 (Folder 13, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 September 3 (Folder 14, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 October 1 (Folder 15, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 September 4 (Folder 16, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1813 July (Folder 17, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders [note found with orders?], undated (Folder 18, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 November 19 (Folder 19, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 September 3 (Folder 20, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 November 21 (Folder 21, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 July 20 (Folder 22, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 July 3 (Folder 23, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 November 24 (Folder 24, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, undated (Folder 25, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 November 21 (Folder 26, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1813 August 27 (Folder 27, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 June 20 (Folder 28, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 July 9 (Folder 29, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 April 25 (Folder 30, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1813 December 17 (Folder 31, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 December 16 (Folder 32, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1813 December 7 (Folder 33, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1814 February 28 (Folder 34, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 June 27 (Folder 35, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1812 April 21 (Folder 36, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1813 December 8 (Folder 37, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1813 August 28 (Folder 38, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1813 August 25 (Folder 39, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders, 1813 July 31 (Folder 40, Box 28)
        - War of 1812 Orders [end of bundle], undated (Folder 41, Box 28)
    - Personal correspondence, 1780 - 1816; 4.2.4; Box: 28 Folders: 42 - 61
      - Letter to Colonel Ebenezer Stevens from Sam Hodgdon in Philadelphia. The letter discusses the sale of land and family matters, 178? January 17 [corner ripped] (Folder 42, Box 28)
      - Alex Hodgdon, Boston, regarding money left in trust by Ebenezer Stevens and interest payable to Ebenezer Stevens, 1783 November 20 (Folder 43, Box 28)
      - Hartford. Thomas Seymour to Colonel Ebenezer Stevens regarding the lot of land owned by Mrs. Stephens in Farmington and suggested sale price., 1785 March 12 (Folder 44, Box 28)
      - Boston Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Alex Hodgdon. Letter discusses family. Alex Hodgdon was the brother of Ebenezer Stevens’ first wife, Rebecca Hodgdon, who died in 1783, 1783 July 22 (Folder 45, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Alex Hodgdon. Letter says he was reelected Treasurer and Receiver General of the Commonwealth, 1788 June 19 (Folder 46, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Alexander Hodgdon, 1792 July 14 (Folder 47, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens regarding business dealings. Letter is from Hartford, 1793 March 18 (Folder 48, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Alex Hodgdon, 1794 September 24 (Folder 49, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Alex Hodgdon, 1794 November 17 (Folder 50, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Margaret Livingston. Her Letter discusses events at Clarmont, fever in Philadelphia and delivery of a turtle on a sloop from Albany, 1799 September 27 (Folder 51, Box 28)
      - Letter from Robert Livingston to Ebenezer Stevens, undated (Folder 52, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Henry Knox regarding a pass for Mrs. Byam and Mrs. Kirby, undated (Folder 53, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Edward Livingston regarding vessels in the port of New York, 1802 July 13 (Folder 54, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from his son George A. Stevens in Bordeaux, 1805 January 18 (Folder 55, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from his son George A. Stevens in Bordeaux, 1805 April (Folder 56, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from Martha Ingersoll in Groton, Massachusetts asking a friend can stay with Stevens while in New York City, 1808 May 24 (Folder 57, Box 28)
      - Letter to Horatio Gates Stevens from his cousin Polly in Hodgdon, 1805 October (Folder 58, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from William Stevens, 1808 (Folder 59, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from his son George A. Stevens, Isle of France, 1808 April 16 (Folder 60, Box 28)
      - Letter to Ebenezer Stevens from J.H. Livingston in Kingston, Jamaica regarding business dealings, 1812 June 1 (Folder 61, Box 28)
    - Miscellany, 1763 - 1839; 4.2.5; Box: 29 Folders: 1 - 8
      - Three typed pages from “A Backward Glance” by Edith Wharton with reminiscences about her Great great grandfather Ebenezer Stevens, undated (Folder 1, Box 29)
      - Genealogy of Ebenezer Stevens and his children written in 1844. Also a typed copy (Folder 2, Box 29)
      - Letters to Lucretia Stevens (wife of Ebenezer Stevens) from her children. Letters include Alexander Hodgdon Stevens, Samuel Stevens, and John Austin Stevens. Also a letter to Ledyard (the brother or [of?] Lucretia Stevens) from John Austin Stevens. Four letters in period 1801-1813 (Folder 3, Box 29)
      - Four bills including appraisal of the value of Benjamin Hodgdon’s house, undated (Folder 4, Box 29)
      - Unsigned correspondence with William Pitt the Elder, Earl of Chatham (7 page letter), 1763 September 27 (Folder 5, Box 29)
      - Published Correspondence of the Earl of Chatham, Volume II (found with 7 page letter), 1839 (Folder 6, Box 29)
      - Published Correspondence of the Earl of Chatham, Volume III (found with 7 page letter), 1839 (Folder 7, Box 29)
      - Published Correspondence of the Earl of Chatham, Volume IIII (found with 7 page letter), 1839 (Folder 8, Box 29)
  - Samuel Stevens, 1809 - 1815; 4.3; About X linear feet Boxes: 29 Folders: 9 - 15
    - Yale degree of Samuel Stevens, undated (Folder 9, Box 29)
    - Yale degree of Samuel Stevens, undated (Folder 10, Box 29)
    - Certificate for Samuel Stevens to practice as in Attorney at law, 1809 (Folder 11, Box 29)
    - Certificate signed by Chief Justice of the Supreme court of New York for Samuel Stevens to be admitted as Counselor at Law, 1815 (Folder 12, Box 29)
    - State of New York certifying Samuel Stevens as Solicitor, 1819 (Folder 13, Box 29)
    - Certificate admitting Samuel Stevens to the Society for Promoting Agriculture and Domestic Manufacturers, undated (Folder 14, Box 29)
    - Meeting of the Bar of New York City to mourn the passing of Samuel Stevens, undated (Folder 15, Box 29)
  - Henry Hewgill Stevens, 1820 - 1849; 4.4; Boxes: 31 - 32 Folders: 1 - 10, 1 - 23
    Series contains business and finance materials, correspondence, and miscellany
    - Business and Finance, 1820 - 1846; 4.4.1; Boxes: 31 Folders: 1 - 10